https://www.archspm.org/privacy/

Report Abuse: Your first call should be to law enforcement.
Report Abuse
Your first call should be to law enforcement.
Click Here to Learn More
MENU
About the ArchdioceseCOVID-19 UpdatesSynodLeadershipPoliciesOfficesFind a ParishFind a Catholic SchoolEventsAnnouncementsCareersContact Us
Your Faith, Your LifeOnline / Outdoor MassMarriageTribunal (Annulments)Catholic Education & Youth FormationLife & Human DignitySacraments & WorshipFaith & DiscipleshipFaith CommunitiesMinisterio LatinoStewardshipMission/Social Outreach
How We ServeSafe EnvironmentChancellorsParish ServicesHR & BenefitsGreat Catholic ParishesDevelopmentFinance & AccountingArchives & RecordsOffice of ConciliationCommunications
Clergy & VocationsClergy ServicesVocationsDeacons & Deacon FormationConsecrated Life
More ResourcesStaff DirectoryOverviewOur HistoryReorganizationEcumenical GuidesPastoral LettersCatholic GlossaryHow Do I…
MENU
About the ArchdioceseCOVID-19 UpdatesSynodLeadershipPoliciesOfficesFind a ParishFind a Catholic SchoolEventsAnnouncementsCareersContact Us
Your Faith, Your LifeOnline / Outdoor MassMarriageTribunal (Annulments)Catholic Education & Youth FormationLife & Human DignitySacraments & WorshipFaith & DiscipleshipFaith CommunitiesMinisterio LatinoStewardshipMission/Social Outreach
How We ServeSafe EnvironmentChancellorsParish ServicesHR & BenefitsGreat Catholic ParishesDevelopmentFinance & AccountingArchives & RecordsOffice of ConciliationCommunications
Clergy & VocationsClergy ServicesVocationsDeacons & Deacon FormationConsecrated Life
More ResourcesStaff DirectoryOverviewOur HistoryReorganizationEcumenical GuidesPastoral LettersCatholic GlossaryHow Do I…
Privacy
Privacy
Welcome to the website of The Archdiocese of Saint Paul and Minneapolis. This site is operated by The Archdiocese of Saint Paul and Minneapolis (“Archdiocese”). This policy states the Archdiocese’s policy relative to the information, including personal data and other information collected from visitors to this website.
Information Collected
When a visitor provides information to the Archdiocese using this website, the Archdiocese may collect personal data from you. The data collected includes the following:
Personal Information. The Archdiocese only collects personally identifiable information on a voluntary basis. This information is provided to the Archdiocese by the visitor through the completion and submission of forms, inquiries, and other similar means. “Personal Information” may include, but is not limited to: a visitor’s name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address.
By voluntarily providing the Archdiocese with Personal Information, the provision of such information indicates the visitor’s consent to the Archdiocese’s use of the Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Provision of Personal Information is an acknowledgment and agreement that such Personal Information may be transferred from the visitor’s current position to the offices and servers of the Archdiocese and authorized third parties.
One of these third parties is MailChimp, through which the Archdiocese sends some of their email newsletters. You may view MailChimp’s Privacy Policy here.
Non-Personal Information. When you interact with the Archdiocese via this website, the Archdiocese receives and stores certain personally non-identifiable information (Non-Personal Information”). Non-Personal Information, which is passively collected using various technologies, cannot be used to identify a specific user. The Archdiocese may store such information itself or in databases owned and maintained by Archdiocesan affiliates, agents, or service providers. The Archdiocese may aggregate personally non-identifiable information to track, for example, the total number of individuals that visit this website, the number of visitors to each page of this website, and the domain names of visitors’ Internet service providers. No Personal Information is available or used in this process.
In connection with the operation of this website, the Archdiocese may employ the use of technology commonly known as “cookies.” A “cookie” is an element of data that a website can send to the Internet browser of a visitor to that website. A “cookie” is not a computer program and has no ability to read data residing on the visitor’s computer or instruct it to perform any step or function. The “cookie” does not extract any Personal Information.
Use of Information Collected
The Archdiocese uses Personal Information a visitor provides in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. If a visitor provides Personal Information for a specific reason, the Archdiocese will use the Personal Information only for the purpose it was provided. The Archdiocese, its subsidiaries, affiliates, and agents may use Personal Information and Non-Personal Information collected through the website to improve the content and functionality of the website. The Archdiocese may disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) comply with a legal obligation, (ii) protect or defend the rights or property of the Archdiocese, (iii) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of visitors to the website, or (iv) protect against legal liability.
Disclosure of Information Collected
The Archdiocese will not sell, license, transmit, or disclose information collected to parties unaffiliated with the Archdiocese unless such sale, license, transmittal, or disclosure is expressly authorized by the visitor or required or permitted by law. In all cases, the Archdiocese will disclose information collected consistent with applicable laws and regulations, and will require the recipient of such information to protect the information and use it only for the purpose it was provided.
Exclusions
This Privacy Policy does not apply to any Personal Information collected by the Archdiocese other than Personal Information collected through this website. This Privacy Policy shall not apply to any unsolicited information provided to the Archdiocese through this website or any other means. This includes, but is not limited to, information posted to any public areas of the website, such as bulletin boards, any ideas for new information, resources, products or services, and other unsolicited submissions. All unsolicited information shall be deemed to be Non-Personal Information and the Archdiocese shall be free to reproduce, use, disclose, and distribute such information to others without limitation or attribution.
Use by Children
The Archdiocese does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any Personal Information through this website. The Archdiocese encourages parents to monitor their children’s Internet usage and online activities.
If there is reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided Personal Information through this website, please contact the Archdiocese and it will endeavor to delete such information.
Security
The Archdiocese takes reasonable precautions to protect visitors to its website and information provided by such visitors from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. Notwithstanding these protective measures, e-mail sent to or from this website may not be secure. Accordingly, visitors should consider the nature of the information sent to the Archdiocese via e-mail.
Hyperlinks to Other Websites
This website contains hyperlinks to other websites not operated or controlled by the Archdiocese (“Third Party Websites”). These hyperlinks are provided for the visitors’ reference only. This Privacy Policy does not apply to Third Party Websites.
The Archdiocese is not responsible for either the privacy policies of Third Party Websites or the validity of information contained therein. Inclusion of hyperlinks to Third Party Websites does not in any manner imply any endorsement of the material on Third Party Websites or association with their owners or operators.
Changes to Privacy Policy
The Archdiocese reserves the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time without prior notice. Continued use of this website shall indicate agreement with the terms of such revised Privacy Policy.
Contact Information
To offer comments about this website or about the information present in this Privacy Policy, please contact the webmaster.
